Brendan Howe

Front-End Web Developer

PROFILE

A front-end junior web developer. Experienced in gathering, analyzing and compiling information from disparate resources into engaging products. My background in the service industry, education and nonprofit radio informs my problem-solving approach of doing more with less.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Seattle — Software Engineering Student

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020

- Full-time, 12-week, 480+ hour immersive coding boot camp graduate.
- Built a strong foundation in web development languages and principles.
- Worked with a team of engineers and UX/UI designers to win a 36-hour in-house hackathon.

Brendan Howe Communications, Seattle, WA — Freelance Writer, Editor and Interview

JAN 2016 - PRESENT

- Plan projects and research extensively prior to interviews.
- Write and conduct interviews with innovative sources in the arts, business and technology for magazine and blog publication.
- Utilize exceptional writing, editing and proofreading skills to produce engaging and error-free content.
- See samples at <u>brendanhowe.net</u>.

Restaurant Industry, CA, WA — Lead Server

JUN 2013 - MAR 2020

- Maintain calm efficiency under sustained, intense pressure.
- Manage daily finances and employee schedule changes.

PROJECTS

TRIPTYCH — Full MERN Stack Application

- Capstone project for General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive boot camp.
- Created with SASS, MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js.
- Users curate their own art gallery. View Triptych.

ESSENTIALS — Full MERN Stack Application

- The winning project for a GA Web Dev and UX/UI team Hackathon.
- Users track and purchase local supplies of pandemic essentials for a variety of outlets. View Essentials.

Seattle, WA

brendan.howe1@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brendan-howe/ github.com/bhowe111

SKILLS

HTML/CSS. JavaScript.

React. Django.

MongoDB. Mongoose.

Heroku. MapBox.

GitHub. Figma.

Google Maps API. jQuery.

Bootstrap. SASS. Materialize.

Python. Express. Node.

Axios. Blender.

SQL. PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

UC Santa Cruz,Santa Cruz, CABA American Studies

AUG 2009 - JUN 2013

Graduated with Honors in the Major

University of Bristol, Bristol, UK — Study Abroad

AUG 2011 - MAY 2012

UCEAP Study Abroad Program